-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
福尔摩斯探案
The Casebook of Sherlock Holmes
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第五季 第二集
S5E02
...早在耶稣出生之前
...long, long before Jesus was born.
那真的是迷失的世界 就在巴西
It is truly the lost world and it's in Brazil.
那是你们妈妈的祖国 也是你们的国家
Your mamma's homeland and your country, too.
永远不要让自己
Never allow yourself
爱一个人爱得太深 Bates先生
to love someone too deeply Mr. Bates.
那会毁了你的
It will destroy you.
你到底还是来了
So you've come.
雷神桥之谜
The Prbolem of Thor Bridge
你接了一件案子 福尔摩斯
You have a case Holmes.
哈 你肯定是传染上了我的观察力
Ha, your faculty of observation is certainly contagious.
它使你马上能够洞悉我的秘密
It has enabled you at once to probe my secret.
是的 我接了一个案子
Yes, I have a case
在一个月的琐事和业务萧条之后
after a month of trivialities and stagnation
现在车轮终于又动起来了
the wheels move once more.
我可以听听吗?
Might I share it?
几乎没什么可说的
There's little to share.
等你吃了那两个煮老的鸡蛋后 我们再讨论吧
We will discuss it after you consume those two hard-boiled eggs,
它们可是我们的临时厨师 优待我们的哦
which our temporary cook has favored us.
这两个鸡蛋的状况
Their condition may not unconnected
应该是跟一期有关
with a copy of the Family Herald
我昨天看到这本杂志 就在在门厅的桌子上
which I observed yesterday on the hall table.
即使是煮蛋这样的小事
Even so trivial a matter as them cooking an egg
也是需要用心的
demands an attention,
这与那本出色的期刊上的爱情传奇
which is incompatible with a love romance
是相互矛盾的
in that excellent periodical.
希望Hudson太太的假期过得愉快
I hope Mrs. Hudson is enjoying her holiday.
你应该听说过Neil Gibson
You've heard of Neil Gibson,
那个金矿之王
the gold king.
你说的是那个美国参议员?
You mean the America senator?
呃 他是西部某个州的参议员
Well he was senator of some western state.
他更为人知的身份是
He's better known as
世界上最伟大的金矿巨头
the greatest gold mining magnet in the world.
是的 我知道这个人
Yes, I know of him.
在英格兰呆了一段时间了吧?
Stayed in England for some time, didn't he?
大约五年前 他在Hampshire
He bought a considerable estate
买了一座相当大的房子
in Hampshire some five years ago.
你也许听说了他妻子的惨死吧
You may have heard of the tragic death of his wife.
哦 怪不得名字听上去那么熟
Oh, that's why the name is familiar.
我不清楚详情
I know nothing of the details.
事实是 这起案件虽然极其轰动
The fact is that the case, although exceedingly sensational
最后却没有什么难办的
appears to present no difficulty.
被告Grace Dunbar小姐的个性
The interesting personality of the accused
虽然有趣
Miss Grace Dunbar
却也无法掩盖清晰的证据
does not obscure the clearness of the evidence.
它们已经被验尸聆讯的陪审团所采信
That is if your taken by the coroner's jury
进入警方的法庭诉讼阶段
and also in the police court proceedings.
这是吃力不讨好的差事 华生
It is a thankless business Watson.
我能够发现事实 但我改变不了事实
I can discover facts, but I cannot change them.
除非出现新的完全出乎意料的事实
Unless some new and entirely unexpected ones come to light
否则我不知道我的委托人 还有什么好期待的
I do not see what my client can hope for.
你的委托人?
Your client?
我快要染上你那种 对故事进行倒叙的习惯了
I'm falling into your involved habit of telling a story back...
我不信这个
I don't believe this.
你得先把它读一读
You must read this first.
亲爱的歇洛克 福尔摩斯先生
Dear Mr. Sherlock Holmes,
我不能眼睁睁地看着
I cannot see the best woman God ever made
上帝所创造的最好的女士步向死亡
go to her death without doing all
而不尽我所能去拯救她
that is possible to save her.
我无法解释
I can't explain things.
甚至连尝试去解释都做不到
I can't even try to explain them
但是我知道
but I know beyond all doubt
Dunbar小姐毫无疑问是无辜的
that Miss. Dunbar is innocent.
您了解事实
You know the facts.
谁又不了解呢?
Who doesn't?
这已经成了全国上下 茶余饭后的谈资了
It has been the gossip of the country
却没有一个声音为她说话
and never a voice raised for her.
最让我发狂的
It's the damned injustice of it all
就是这种该死的不公平
that makes me crazy.
那位女士心地善良
That woman has a heart
连苍蝇都不忍心打死
that wouldn't let her kill a fly.
也许我手中握有 连我自己都没有发觉的线索
Maybe I have a clue and don't know it.
不管怎么说 只要您能救她
Anyway, all I know and all I have and all I am
我的所知所有连同我这个人 都将听候您的差遣
are for your use if only you can save her.
你没时间细读所有这些剪报的内容
You hardly have time to master all these cuttings
所以要是你感兴趣的话
so I must give it to you in a lecture
我可以把此事的来龙去脉
if you're going to take an intelligent interest
给你详细地说一说
in the proceedings.
Gibson先生 据我所知
Mr. Gibson, as I understand is a man
娶了一位巴西太太
who married a Brazilian wife,
对于他的太太我完全不了解
and for who I know nothing
除了知道她青春已逝
except that she was past her prime,
甚为不幸
which was all the more unfortunate.
她请了一位很有魅力的家庭女教师
She has a very attractive governess
负责两个小孩的教育
who superintended the education of two children.
这是涉及此事的三个人
These are the three people concerned.
背景就是那所古老的庄园豪宅
The scene is the grand old manor house.
至于这起悲剧嘛...
As to the tragedy,
就发生在湖上的一座桥上
it takes place across a bridge over the lake
在宅子半英里外
half mile from the house.
一个猎场看守人夜里在桥上
The wife was found late at night by a gamekeeper
发现了这位太太
on that bridge.
她身着晚宴礼服
She was clad in her dinner dress
脑袋被一颗左轮手枪子弹打穿了
and a revolver bullet through her brain.
尸体附近没有找到凶器
No weapon was found near her
当地找不到任何与谋杀有关的线索
and there was no local clue as to her murder.
她附近找不到任何凶器的线索 华生
No weapon near her mark that Watson.
我说的是不是太简要了? 你能不能听得明白?
Is this too condensed, or can you follow it clearly?
可以的 很清楚
No, no, it's all very clear
但是为什么要怀疑家庭女教师呢?
but why suspect the governess?
呃...首先 有一些非常直接的证据
Well, in the first place there was some very direct evidence.
死去的女士身上有一张
The dead woman had a note upon her
家庭女教师署名的便条
making an appointment at the bridge.
约死者在桥上见面
And signed by the governess.
Gibson先生派他的农庄总管去找警察
Mr. Gibson sent his farm manager for the police
自己留守在尸体边
and stayed with the body
他要求不得移动现场的任何东西
insisting that nothing should be removed
直到警察在11点过后到达
until the police arrived just after 11:00.
然后发现了凶器...
Then there is the evidence of the revolver
一把发射过子弹的左轮手枪
with one discharged chamber.
Dunbar小姐
Miss. Dunbar.
而且手枪的口径
And a caliber
与子弹吻合
which corresponded with the bullet.
是的 我在这上面读到了
Yes, I see it here.
是在她衣柜的抽屉里发现的
It was found in the drawer of her wardrobe.
她衣柜的抽屉里
In the drawer of her wardrobe.
相当具有毁灭性的证据
That's pretty damning.
两个陪审团也是这么想的
So the two juries thought.
案件现在提交到了Winchester巡回审判庭
It is now referred to the Assizes at Winchester.
动机呢?
And the motive?
Gibson先生是一位很有魅力的男士
Mr. Gibson is a very attractive man.
如果他妻子死了
If his wife dies
谁能比那位年轻女士
who more likely to succeed her
更有可能当她的继任者呢?
than the young lady who had already
据大家所说
by all accounts received
她的雇主可是对她十分殷勤啊
pressing attentions from her employer.
爱情 财富 权力
Love, fortune, power,
全都取决于一位中年男士
all depending upon one middle-aged man,
用心险恶 华生 十分险恶
ugly Watson, very ugly.
而且她无法给出不在场的证明
Nor could she prove an alibi.
相反的 她不得不承认
On the contrary, she had to admit
她当晚九点的确上了桥
that she was down to the bridge by 9:00.
有个仆人看见她匆匆往那儿赶去
A servant had seen her hurrying there.
似乎结局已经注定了
Well, it really does seem final.
然而...华生
And yet Watson,
然而...
and yet.
如果我没搞错的话
Unless I'm mistaken that is our client
应该是我们的委托人提早到了
considerably before his time.
有位先生要见您 先生
Gentleman to see you, sir.
Neil Gibson先生吗?
Mr. Neil Gibson?
不 先生 不是他
No, sir, not him.
是一位叫Bates的先生
His name is Bates
看上去有些恼怒
and he looks a bit aggravated.
谢谢 Billy
Thank you, Billy.
我的时间不多 Bates先生
I have only a short time, Mr. Bates.
我知道Gibson先生就快到了
I know Mr. Gibson is coming.
我是他庄园的总管
I am manager of his estate.
福尔摩斯先生 他是个恶棍!
Mr. Holmes, he's a villain,
一个可恨的恶棍
an infernal villain.
措辞很强烈啊 Bates先生
Strong words Mr. Bates.
呃 我不得不加重语气 福尔摩斯先生
Well, I have to be emphatic Mr. Holmes.
时间有限
The time is so limited.
我恰好不想让他发现我在这儿
I'll not have him find me here for the world.
而你是他的总管
And you're his manager.
噢 我已经告知他了
Oh, I've given him notice.
再过几周 我就将摆脱他那该死的奴役
In a couple of weeks I shall have shaken off his cursed slavery.
他是个严苛的人 福尔摩斯先生
He's a hard man Mr. Holmes,
各方面都很严苛
hard to all about him.
不过他的妻子是他的主要受害者
But his wife was his chief victim.
他对她非常残忍
He was brutal to her.
噢 是的 先生 十分残忍
Oh, yes, sir, brutal.
我不知道她是怎么死的
Now how she come by her death I do not know,
不过他让她的生活痛苦不堪
but let me tell you he made her life a misery.
她是一个来自热带的人
She was a creature of the tropics,
你应该都知道了 她是个巴西人
a Brazilian by birth as you no doubt know.
是的 我知道 请接着说 接着说
Yes, I understand. Please continue, continue.
呃 具有热带的血统 热带的天性
Well tropical by birth, tropical by nature,
她是太阳的女儿 充满了热情
she was a child of the sun and of passion.
她全身心地爱他
She loved him as only such women can love.
我们都同情她
We all felt for her.
憎恶他对待她的方式
Hated him for the way he treated her.
不过他总是花言巧语又狡诈多端
But he's plausible and cunning.
我要告诉你的就是这些
And that's all I have to tell you.
不要被他的表象迷惑了
Don't take him at face value.
在他的假面背后还有更多的东西
There is more behind.
现在我得走了
Now I'll go.
不 不要挽留我
No, please don't detain me.
他就要到了
He's almost due.
哇哇哇
Well, well, well.
Gibson先生有着很好的忠诚的一家
Mr. Gibson has a nice loyal household.
"很有价值"才是该用的字眼
Rewarding is a useful one.
Gibson先生 请直接上楼 先生
Mr. Gibson, straight upstairs, sir.
这是我的朋友和同事 华生医生
This is my friend and colleague Dr. Watson.
我在这儿明确声明 福尔摩斯先生
Let me say right here Mr. Holmes,
在这件事上你完全不用担心钱的问题
money is nothing to me in this business.
如果能对你发掘真相有所帮助
You can burn it if it's any use
你把钱烧了也没关系
enlightening you to the truth.
这位女士是无辜的 必须还她清白
This woman is innocent. This woman has to be cleared.
这事就靠你来做了
It's up to you to do it.
说说你的数目吧
Now name your figure.
我的职业收费有着固定的标准
My professional charges are at a fixed rate.
我通常不做改变
I do not vary them save
完全免费的情况除外
when I remit them altogether.
哦 如果金钱对你来说没有什么影响
Well, if money makes no difference to you
那就想想名声吧
think of the reputation.
如果你能澄清这个案子
If you pull this off every newspaper
英格兰和美国的每一份报纸 都会大肆宣传的
in England and America will be booming.
两个大陆的人们都会谈论你
You'll be the talk of two continents.
我觉得我不需要什么宣传 Gibson先生
I do not think I'm in need of booming Mr. Gibson.
让我们着眼事实吧
Please let us get down to the facts.
呃 大多数主要的事实
Well, you'll find most of the main ones
你都能在媒体的报道中看到
in the press reports.
我觉得也没什么好补充的了
I don't think I can add much to them,
不过如果还有你还有什么 需要进一步弄清的
but if there's anything you'd wish more light on,
我可以告诉你
well I'm here to give it.
只有一点
Well there is just one point.
是什么?
What is it?
你和Dunbar小姐确切的关系是什么?
What are your exact relations with Miss. Dunbar?
我想  福尔摩斯先生
I suppose you are within your rights,
问这样的问题 也许是你的权利和职责
maybe doing your duty in asking such a question Mr. Holmes.
的确如此
We will agree to suppose so.
那么我可以向你保证
Then I can assure you
我们的关系一直是而且完全是
that our relations were always and entirely
雇主与一位年轻女雇员的关系
those of an employer that awards a young lady
她和小孩相处的时间以外
whom he never conversed with or even saw
我从未跟她说过话甚至是见过她
save when she was in the company of his children.
我是个大忙人  Gibson先生
I'm rather a busy man Mr. Gibson.
对于毫无意义的谈话 我既无时间也无兴趣
I don't have time or taste for aimless conversations.
祝您早安
I wish you good morning.
你这样说到底什么意思 福尔摩斯先生?
What the devil do you mean by this Mr. Holmes?
你拒绝接受我的案子吗?
Do you dismiss my case?
不 Gibson先生 我拒绝接受的是你
No, Mr. Gibson, I dismiss you.
就算是没有这种虚假的信息
The case is quite sufficiently complicated
给我增添麻烦 案子本身就已经够复杂了
without the added difficulty of false information.
你的意思是我在撒谎喽?
Meaning that I lied?
我尽可能表达得委婉一些
I tried to express it as delicately as I could,
不过如果你坚持这样说
but if you insist upon the word
我也不否认
I will not contradict you.
别焦躁  Gibson先生
Don't be noisy Mr. Gibson.
我发现在用完早餐以后 任何争吵都是非常令人难受的
I find after breakfast any argument most unsettling.
我想在户外散一下步
I suggest a little stroll in the open air
再安静地做些思考
and some quiet thought
会对你非常有好处的
will be greatly to your advantage.
比你更强的人我都打败过 福尔摩斯先生
I've broken stronger men than you Mr. Holmes.
惹恼我的人从来不曾有过好下场
Nobody crosses me and gets the better of it.
许多人对我这样说过 可是我现在还好好地在这儿坐着
So many have said so yet here I am.
华生 他得学的事情还多着呢
Well, Watson he has a great deal yet to learn.
你到底是怎么知道 他和家庭女教师之间的关系的?
How on earth did you know about his relationship with the governess?
虚张声势的 华生 虚张声势
Bluff, Watson, bluff.
我觉得 他信里那种热切的非公事话的口吻
I considered the passionate and unbusinesslike tone of his letter
与他的举止和外表并不相符
contrasted with his manner and appearance.
显然他对那名被指控的女士
It was pretty clear there was some deep emotion
而不是死者
centered upon the accused woman
怀有深沉的感情
rather than the victim.
我于是对他虚张声势
I bluffed him by giving the impression
让他以为我对此已经完全清楚
that I was absolutely certain of it.
而事实上你只是有所怀疑罢了
When in reality you were only suspicious.
你觉得他还会回来吗?
Do you think he'll come back?
他肯定会回来的
He is sure to come back.
他非回来不可
He must come back.
噢 不不不 我亲爱的华生
Oh, no, no, my dear Watson
恐怕你在你的记录里
I fear you will not improve
再添上雷神桥之谜
any reputation I have acquired
对提高我的声名也没有什么帮助的
by adding the Thor Bridge mysteries,
我担心我做出了严重错误的判断
your annals I fear I made a serious misjudgment.
福尔摩斯 参议员也许是没有回来
Holmes, the senator may not have returned
但他的来信确定无疑
but surely his letter
是代表Dunbar小姐聘用了你
has engaged you on behalf of Miss. Dunbar.
她才是那个处在危难中的人
She's the one in need.
难道我们不去拜访她一下吗
Might we not pay her a visit?
去Winchester监狱?
In the cells of Winchester?
那需要得到官方的许可
That will require official permits.
呃 我们有办法可以申请到
Well we have the means to apply.
当然不是很符合职业道德的途径
Of course it may not be quite ethical.
但却很实用 华生 很实用
But practical Watson, practical.
我要祝贺你
I congratulate you.
你把我们的难题解决了吗 华生?
You solved our problem Watson?
某个多管闲事的小职员
Some officious little pip-squeak of a clerk
对我们的信和官方许可提出了质疑
queried both the letter and our home office permit.
他要求Gibson本人 亲自授权
He demanded a personal authorization from Gibson himself.
不过你还是解决了?
But you sorted it out?
幸好交了好运
Only by the good fortune
碰到了她的律师Cummings先生
of meeting her lawyer Mr. Cummings.
在他的担保下 我们可以听她做一次简短的陈述
He secured a brief audience with her.
Joyce Cummings先生
Mr. Joyce Cummings, a man with a rising reputation
他的声名鹊起当然是得益于她
that is certainly in her favor.
能在这里见到您真是上帝的恩赐 福尔摩斯先生
It really is providence to see you here Mr. Holmes.
她的案子两天后就要开庭了
Her trial is in two days
而我实在是智穷计尽
and I really am at my wits ends
找不到任何可以挽救她的证据
to find any evidence to save her.
她是否承认 写过便条并与Gibson太太见过面?
Did she admit to writing the note and keeping the rendezvous with Mrs. Gibson?
她别无选择啊
She has little choice.
不过除了这点以外
But beyond that I have advised her
-我还是建议她不要认罪 -没错
-to reserve her defense. -Quite so.
这位是歇洛克.福尔摩斯先生
This is Mr. Sherlock Holmes
还有他的同事华生医生
and his colleague Dr. Watson.
你的雇主Gibson先生聘请我
Your employer Mr. Gibson has engaged me
来调查这起令人不快的事件
to look into this unhappy matter.
噢 对Gibson先生我非常感激
Oh, I'm very grateful to Mr. Gibson.
对我的指控维持不变
It is incredible that the charge against me
真是难以置信
has been sustained.
我还以为在初级法庭上
I thought the whole thing would clear itself up
整件事情就可以得到澄清了呢
in the police court.
亲爱的小姐 我请你不要存在任何幻想
My dear, dear I beg of you to have no illusions.
Cummings先生会向你表明
Mr. Cummings here will assure you
现在所有的证据都是对你不利的
all the cards at present are against you.
Gibson先生相信你的清白
Mr. Gibson is convinced of your innocence
但如果假装说你的处境不是十分危险
but it would be a cruel deception to pretend
那将是对你的残忍欺骗
that you're not in very great danger.
我会实话实说的
I will conceal nothing.
你和Gibson先生的妻子之间
What were the true relations between you
真正的关系如何?
and Mr. Gibson's wife?
许可...什么许可?
Permit... what permit?
你怎么敢如此造次 福尔摩斯先生?
How dare you take this liberty Mr. Holmes?
Gibson先生
Mr. Gibson.
还有你 Cummings
And you Cummings,
我雇佣你不是要你来联合对我耍阴谋的
I did not engage you sir to conspire against me.
这些人说得了我的许可 完全是捏造
These men are here under false pretenses.
我并没有授权让他们进行这次探访
I did not authorize their visit.
他们都是些骗子
They're deceivers.
我要求他们立即离开
I demand their removal at once.
Gibson先生 你心智不清
You have made a disturbance Mr. Gibson,
可以进疯人院了
worthy of bedlam.
说这话我非让人把你碾碎不可 福尔摩斯
I'll have you crushed for this Holmes.
是嘛 这对你可没什么好处
Well it'll profit you nothing.
Holmes先生
Mr. Holmes.
我们要走了 警官
We are leaving superintendent.
Cummings先生
Mr. Cummings.
暂时就到这吧 Dunbar小姐
For the moment Miss. Dunbar.
你必须信任歇洛克.福尔摩斯
You must put your faith in Sherlock Holmes.
你是...?
Mr?
Ferguson
Ferguson.
街对面的博物馆
There is an excellent exhibition
正举行非常精彩的展览
at the museum across the street.
我郑重向你推荐
I recommend it to you.
- 博物馆五点钟关门 - 这次起诉 警官先生 完全是误会
The museum closes at 5:00.
1578年做气泡玻璃的工人
The copy of the lease
所签订的契约
of the buck-boat glass workers dated 1578.
这些法国人 是你的什么亲戚吗?
These Huguenots, are they any relations of yours?
也许吧
Possibly.
Potel先生 和Leve Stoke城的造纸
Monsieur Potel and this paper making of laver stoke.
他们做钞票的历史
They've had the manufacture of bank notes
已经有一百多年了
for over 100 years.
是嘛 很高兴得知
Well it's good to know
在你家某个地方还有些钱
there's money somewhere in your family.
下午好 Ferguson先生
Good afternoon Mr. Ferguson.
Neil Gibson先生想见你
Mr. Neil Gibson wishes to see you
时间是明早11点 在雷神宅邸
at Thor Place at 11:00 tomorrow morning.
今晚可能更方便些
This evening will be more convenient.
早上11点 福尔摩斯先生
The morning, 11:00 Mr. Holmes.
会不会派汽车来接我们?
Will a motor be sent for us?
有趟火车 可以直接带你们到雷神村
There is a train which will take you to Thor Village.
Gibson先生是个忙碌的人
Mr. Gibson is a busy man.
他希望你能准时到达
He expects punctuality.
-你怎么知道他的态度会有转变? -我赌了一把
-How did you know that he was going to turn? -I gambled,
Dunbar小姐脸上的表情
there's been enough of an impression
可以替我们赢得好感
upon Ms. Dunbar to turn us back into favor.
我们毕竟是她唯一的希望
We are after all her only hope.
华生 现在我们得找家舒适的旅馆 来度过这一晚
Now Watson we must find a comfortable inn for the night
这样我们才能在明早9点
so that we can arrive punctually at Thor Place
准时到达雷神宅邸
at 9:00 in the morning.
我以为他说的是11点
I thought he said 11:00.
9点 华生
9:00 Watson
我们去见当地警局的Coventry警官
to meet Sergeant Coventry of the local police.
任何情况下 福尔摩斯先生
In all events Mr. Holmes
我更乐意是您而不是苏格兰场来
I'd rather have you than Scotland Yard.
如果苏格兰场插手一件案子
If the Yard gets called into a case,
案子破了当地的警方也得不到任何功劳
the local loses all credit for success
要是破不了也许就得背黑锅
and may be blamed for failure.
我听说您就不会玩花样
Now you play it straight so I've heard.
这件事我根本不必出面
I need not appear in the matter at all.
您真是太大度了
That's very handsome of you.
而我知道您的朋友华生医生也值得信任
And your friend Dr. Watson can be trusted I know.
我有个问题要问你
Now there is one question I'd like to ask you
不过我只问您一个人
but I breath it to no soul but you.
您觉不觉得
Don't you think there might be a case
也许案子对Neil Gibson先生本人不利?
against Mr. Neil Gibson himself?
就仆人们所说
According to the servants
他吃完晚餐就进了书房
he retired to his study after dinner
在11点来警报之前
and had no company at all
根本就没人陪伴
until the alarm at 11:00.
是的 我考虑过Gibson先生
Yes I've been considering Mr. Gibson.
这些美国人比起我们这里的人 更热衷于用手枪
These Americans are readier with their pistols than our folk are.
那就是他的手枪 你知道吧
It was his pistol, you know.
一对中的一把
One of a pair he had.
一对中的一把?
One of a pair?
另一把在哪里?
Where is the other?
这些先生们总是有
Well these gentlemen have all kinds of firearms
这样那样的各式各样的武器
of one sort or another.
我们没有真正比对过那把特殊的手枪
We never quite matched that particular pistol.
盒子是根据一对手枪定造的
The box was made for two.
这就是尸体所在的地方
Now, this is where the body lay.
我从报上读到
I gathered from the press reports
子弹是近距离发射的
that the shot was fired at close quarters.
距离非常近 先生
Very close sir.
就在右侧太阳穴附近?
Near the right temple?
右侧太阳穴往后一点 先生
Just behind it, sir.
尸体的姿势如何?
How did the body lie?
仰面躺下 先生
On the back, sir.
没有搏斗的痕迹 没有脚印 没有凶器
No trace of a struggle, no mark, no weapons.
她的左手攥着
The short note from Ms. Dunbar
Dunbar小姐写的短笺
was clutched in her left hand.
攥着?
Clutched?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
我们几乎都没法掰开她的手指
We could hardly open her fingers.
这是最重要的一点
That is of the greatest importance.
这一点排除了一种说法
It excludes the idea
就是有人在她死后把便条放到她手里
that anybody could have placed it there
以制造假证据
after death to furnish a false clue.
但是天哪
But dear me,
我记得便条写得十分简短
the note as I remember was quite short.
是的 "9点到雷神桥 G. Dunbar"
Yes, be at Thor Bridge 9:00 G. Dunbar,
是不是那样写的?
wasn't that it?
的确如此 先生
So it was, sir.
便条意思模糊 不是吗?
The point of the note is obscured, is it not.
呃 先生 我这样说也许有些鲁莽
Well, sir, it seemed if I may be bold as to say so
这可是整个案件中唯一真正清晰的一点啊
the only real clear point in the whole case.
假设便条不是伪造的
Assuming the note is genuine.
她肯定是之前的某个时间收到的
She certainly received it some time before,
比方说一两个钟头之前
say an hour or two.
那么她为什么还把它握在左手上呢?
Why was she then clasping it in the left hand?
在会面过程中她不必再参考其内容
She had no need to refer to it in the interview.
这一点看上去不是很值得注意吗?
Does that not seem remarkable?
呃 先生 正如你所说的 也许是值得关注
Well sir, as you put it, perhaps it does.
那个很古怪啊
That is curious.
噢 是的 先生 我们注意到了
Oh, yes, sir, we noticed that.
我觉得是某个过路人干的
I expect it's been done by some passer-by.
干这个需要下手很重
Took some violence to do that.
这不是来自上方的猛烈撞击 而是来自底下
It was a hard knock not from above, but below.
你看见栏杆的底端了吗 华生?
You see some lower end of the parapet Watson?
是的 和尸体所在位置
Yes and in a direct line
刚好成一直线
with the position of the body.
也许无关紧要
It's probably of no matter.
你说过没有脚印?
No footprints you say.
是的 地面如钢铁般坚硬 先生
The ground was iron hard sir.
完全没有足迹
No marks at all.
那我们在这里也没有什么需要知道的了
Then we have nothing more to learn here.
你来早了 福尔摩斯先生
You are early Mr. Holmes.
准时的情况通常就是如此  Ferguson先生
It is often the case with punctuality Mr. Ferguson.
Gibson先生在开会
Mr. Gibson is in a meeting.
他还不能见你
He is not ready to see you.
我来招待他们 Ferguson
I'll take care of them Ferguson.
很高兴见到你们 先生们
I'm very glad to see you gentlemen.
既然我们来早了一点
As we are a little early
也许我们可以看看枪火室?
perhaps we can see the gun room?
一个树敌不少的人
A man who has his enemies.
噢 是的 要是你们了解他的为人和处事
Oh, yes if you knew him and his methods.
他睡觉时还把一把上了膛的左轮手枪
He sleeps with a loaded revolver
放在他的床头柜里
in a drawer by his bed.
他是一个很暴力的人 先生
He's a man of violence, sir.
你有没有见到过他殴打他的妻子?
Have you ever seen him strike his wife?
是的 不只一次
Yes, more than once.
我们的金矿之王的私生活 可不像金子那么熠熠生辉啊
Our gold king does not seem to shine in private life.
福尔摩斯 这里
Holmes, here.
这就是装凶器的盒子
That's the box that contained the murder weapon.
一对中的一把
It was one of a pair.
另外一把失踪了
The other is missing.
Ferguson先生肯定知道
Mr. Ferguson is sure to know
你在陪同我们
that your consorting with us
对此你不担忧吗?
does that hold no alarm for you?
现在他伤害不了我的
There's nothing he can do to hurt me now.
那麻烦你带我们去学习室好吗?
Perhaps you'll be so kind as to show us the schoolroom?
孩子们在哪里?
Where are the children?
送去美国了
Sent away on a visit to America.
一目了然啊
(unintelligible)
他们从母亲那遗传了巴西人的特点
Their Brazilian heritage from their mother's side.
Dunbar小姐应该是个不错的老师
Miss. Dunbar must seem to be a remarkable teacher.
孩子们非常爱她
The children doted on her.
瞧见了吧 华生
See Watson,
Ricardo Franco丘陵
the Ricardo Franco Hills.
看看这些无法攀登的悬崖
See the unscaleable cliffs
从未留下过时间和人类的足迹
which time and the foot of man have never touched,
开天辟地时留下的怪兽
where monsters from the dawn of history
也许还在山崖间徘徊
might still roam.
那是Martins 一位印第安猎手
That's Martins, the Indian hunter.
我知道这个人
I know about him.
他的残害对象都是妇女和孩子 令人同情
His victims, women and children, pitiful.
你是不是说Maria Gibson
Would you say that Maria Gibson
嫉妒Dunbar小姐
was jealous of Miss. Dunbar
以及她对孩子们的影响?
and her influence over the children?
不 他们夫妇之间的爱依然存在
No, there was no love lost between them.
但那是因为她看出
But that was because she could see her husband
她的丈夫也中了那位女士的魔咒了
was under the lady's spell too.
从这滚出去 Bates
Get out of here Bates.
Bates先生的看法与此事无关 福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Bates's views are not relevant Mr. Holmes.
他对我已故妻子的迷恋 导致他歪曲了事实
They're distorted by his infatuation for my late wife.
谁知道呢 Gibson先生
Who knows, Mr. Gibson,
哪些是有关的哪些又是无关的呢
what is and what is not relevant.
你活像是位外科医生
You're like a surgeon who wants every symptom
在做出诊断前总要问清每一个症状
before he could give a diagnosis.
因为每一个病人都有着自己的理由
As any a patient has reason in deceiving
要去欺骗他的医生 隐瞒事实
his surgeon who conceals the facts.
我可以向你保证
I can assure you
我和Dunbar小姐之间的关系
that the relations between Miss. Dunbar and myself
与此案无关
do not touch this case.
我想这个该由我自己来判断
I'm sure that is for me to decide.
大多数男人在他们心灵的某个角落里
Most men have a little private reserve
总为自己保留着一块私人的空间
in some corner of their souls
他们不希望他人去窥探这个空间
where they don't welcome intruders.
你突然间侵入了我的这个空间
You burst suddenly into mine.
你到底想要什么?
What is it you want?
真相
The truth.
我在巴西掘金的时候遇到了我妻子
I met my wife when I was gold hunting in Brazil.
她是Manaos一位政府官员的女儿
She was the daughter of a government official in the Manaos.
即使是现在用我热情已逝的眼光来看
Even now as I look back with a colder eye
她还是有着一种热情奔放的
she had a rich passionate nature,
热带的 情绪不稳定的本性
tropical, ill-balanced,
与我所认识的美国女人有着很大的不同
very different from the American women I'd known.
直到激情消逝
It was only when the romance had passed
我才开始意识到
that I realized we had nothing,
我们之间毫无共同之处
absolutely nothing in common.
我的爱渐渐淡去
My love faded
但你知道女人爱的方式
but you know the wonderful way of women.
不管我怎么做也不能让她不再爱我
Do what I might, nothing could turn her from me.
如果说我对她苛刻 甚至是残忍
If I'd been harsh to her, even brutal,
那是因为我知道
it was because I knew that if I could kill her love
如果我能让她不再爱我甚至恨我
or turn it to hate
那对我们两人来说都会好受些
it would be easier for us both.
但是什么也改变不了她
But nothing changed her.
在这些英国的丛林中
She still adored me in these English woods
她对我的爱
as she had adored me 20 years before
一如20年前在亚马逊河畔
on the banks of the Amazon.
接着Dunbar小姐就出现了
Then came Miss. Dunbar.
她同样是位非常美丽的女士
She is also a very beautiful woman
我向你承认
and I'll admit to you that I could not live
生活在同一屋檐下每天接触她
under the same roof in daily contact with her
不对她产生爱慕是不可能的
without feeling a passionate regard for her.
你能因此责怪我吗 福尔摩斯先生?
You blame me Mr. Holmes?
你有这样的情感我不会怪你
I don't blame you for feeling it.
我要怪你向她表达了你的感情
I should blame you for expressing it
要知道她还是在你的庇护下的
since she was under your protection.
噢 也许吧
Well maybe so.
我不会把我的本性说得比实际更好
I'm not pretending to be any better than I am.
我想在我的一生中
I guess all of my life I've been a man
我要什么东西我都会伸手去争取
that's reached out his hand for what he wanted.
而这个女人以及她的爱
And I never wanted anything more
是我最想得到的东西了
than the love and possession of that woman.
我就是这样告诉她的
I told her so.
是嘛?
You did, did you?
我说如果可以的话我会娶她
I said if I could I'd marry her,
不过这却不是我力所能及的事情
but it was out of my power.
钱不是问题
Money was no object.
我会尽我所能让她快乐
I'd do all I could to make her happy,
舒适
comfortable.
你非常慷慨
Very generous of you.
听着 福尔摩斯先生
Now see here Mr. Holmes
我是来找你是为了证据的问题 而不是道德的问题
I came to you on a question of evidence, not morals.
我不是要你来批评我
I'm not asking for criticism.
我只不过是看在那位女士的份上
It is only for the lady's sake
才接下这个案子
that I take on this case at all.
她所受到的指控
Nothing that she's accused of is worse
并不比你所承认的更坏
than what you yourself have admitted,
你说你试图去毁掉一个
that you've tried to ruin a defenseless girl
生活在你屋檐底下却毫无防备能力的女孩
who was under your roof.
也许有些像你这样的有钱人会反驳我
You know some of you rich men must retort
不过在这个世上并非一切对他人的冒犯
but all the world cannot be bribed
靠金钱的收买就能得到谅解
into condoning your offenses.
我自己也是这样想的
That's how I feel myself about it.
现在我要感谢上帝我的计划没能实现
Now I thank God my plans did not work out.
她完全不买我的帐
She'd have none it.
她想要马上离开这座房子
She wanted to leave the house instantly.
那她怎么还没走?
But why did she not?
还有别人得依靠她
Others were dependent upon her
对她来说
and it was no light matter for her
让他们失望可不是件小事
to let them down.
我向她发誓 再也不会骚扰她了
When I'd sworn that she should never be molested again.
于是她同意留下来
She consented to stay.
不过还有另外一个原因
But there was another reason.
她知道她对我的影响力
She knew the influence that she had over me,
比世上任何其它的影响更为强烈
that it was stronger than any other influence in the world.
她想利用这种影响做些好事
She wanted to use it for good.
你太残忍了
You're cruel.
你毁掉那些无法奋起抵抗你的好人
You destroy good people who can't stand up to you.
并非每一个人都有你那样的力量
Not everyone shares your strength.
难道你不明白吗?
Can't you see that?
你管它叫公平竞争
You call it a fair fight,
但其实那不公平
but it isn't fair.
她的理解很不同
She saw it different.
她认为一个人过多的财富
She believed that a fortune for one man
不应该建立在
that was more than he needed
上万个被毁灭的
should not be built on 10,000 ruined men
毫无生活来源的人身上
who were left without the means of life.
对你的孩子你显示出了如此多的柔情与爱
With your children you show such tenderness and love.
用同样的方式对待这个世界吧
Treat the world in the same way.
她发现我肯听她的话
She found that I listened to what she said.
于是她就留了下来
So she stayed.
接着就发生了这件事情
And then this came along.
Gibson先生 你能不能对此说说看法?
Mr. Gibson, can you throw any light upon it?
有一种解释 福尔摩斯先生
One explanation, I give it to you Mr. Holmes
不管是不是真的
for what it's worth.
毫无疑问我的妻子极端嫉妒
There's no doubt that my wife was bitterly jealous.
她也许计划要谋杀Dunbar小姐
She might have planned to murder Miss. Dunbar
或者用枪威胁她
or threaten her with a gun
想吓唬她离开我们
and so frighten her into leaving us.
也许当时有一场混战
Maybe there was a scuffle.
枪走火了 打中了持枪的人
The gun went off and shot the woman who held it.
是的 是有这样一种可能
Yes, it is a possibility.
它是故意谋杀意外的唯一可能
It is the only alternative to deliberate murder.
不过她完全予以否认
But she utterly denies it.
这样的假设怎么能推翻得了呢?
What is against such a supposition?
Dunbar小姐本人就行
Miss. Dunbar herself.
还有一天就要开庭了
She has just one day left before the trial.
你必须允许我再次去探访她
You must grant me permission to visit her once more.
如果在你的一生中 福尔摩斯 你曾经展示过你的能力
If ever in your life you showed your powers, Holmes,
现在就把它们用在这个案子中吧
put them into this case now.
不过我无法向你保证
But I cannot promise you
我所得出的结论就是你想要的
that my conclusions will be such as you desire.
走吧 华生
Come Watson.
我们有几个生死攸关的问题
We have several vital questions
得去问问这位年轻的女士
to ask this young lady
我得承认
and I must confess that the case would seem to be
要不是因为一件事情
a very black one against her
这个案子确实会对她十分不利
if it were not for one thing.
什么事情?
What is that?
在她衣柜里发现了手枪
The finding of a pistol in her wardrobe.
那似乎是所有证据中最具毁灭性的
That seems to be the most damning incident of all.
并非如此 华生
Not so Watson.
这是我希望的唯一所在
It is my only firm ground for hope.
我们必须寻找事物间的联系
We must look for consistency.
在缺少联系的地方
Where there is a want of it,
我们就得怀疑存在着欺骗
we must suspect deception.
走吧 福尔摩斯
Come on Holmes,
Dunbar小姐还指望我们呢
Miss. Dunbar is depending on us.
华生 设想你自己站在Dunbar小姐的位置上
Watson visualize yourself in the character
预谋用一种冷酷的方式
of Miss. Dunbar with a cold premeditated fashion
除掉她的对手
is about to get rid of her rival.
你会怎样行动 会想些什么?
What would be your actions and your thinking?
呃 我已经写过便条了
Well I've written a note.
受害人也来了
The victim has come.
我从枪火室里拿了手枪
I've taken the weapon from the gunroom.
犯下了罪行
The crime is done.
很娴熟 说得很完整
Workman like and complete,
现在是武器了
and now the weapon.
当然
Of course.
没错 华生
Precisely Watson.
那些深渊也许将永远把它隐藏
Those depths would hide it forever.
你最好的朋友不会认为你是个善谋的人
Your best friends would hardly call you a schemer,
然而我还是很难想像你把它带回家
yet I cannot picture you carrying it home
放进你的衣柜
and putting it in your wardrobe,
那可是第一个会被搜查的地方
the very first place that would be searched.
比如说这把手枪
This revolver for example,
她宣称完全不知道它的存在
she destains all knowledge of it.
你是说手枪是被放进她的衣柜的
You're saying that it was placed in her wardrobe,
不过是谁干的呢?
but by who?
某个想让她获罪的人
By someone who wished to incriminate her.
啊 Cummings
Ah, Cummings.
Dunbar小姐
Miss. Dunbar we have had lengthy conversations
我们和Gibson先生进行了一次长谈
with Mr. Gibson and he has informed us
他把你们的关系以及你的清白
of your relations with him
都告诉了我们
and of your innocence in the matter.
你就不必再重复
But you need not pain yourself
徒增你的烦恼了
with that part of the story.
不过我们的确需要了解
But we do need to know something,
你对Gibson太太的感觉
of your feelings towards Mrs. Gibson.
我不想亵渎Gibson太太的在天之灵
I had no wish to wrong Mrs. Gibson.
不过她从肉体的角度
But she loved her husband
狂热地爱着她的丈夫
so vividly in a physical sense
以至于她无法理解
that she could hardly understand
我和他之间那种心灵的乃至精神上的契合
the mental even spiritual tie which held him to me
她也无法想像我仅仅是...
or imagined that it was only my desire
想影响他去做些好事
to influence his power for good
才在他家里留了下来
which kept me under his roof.
我现在知道了我留下来是个错误
I can see now that I was wrong to stay.
留在这个是非之地
Nothing could have justified me in remaining
成为一场悲剧的导火线
where I was a cause of such unhappiness.
我的委托人也许不想说起它
My client may be loathe to mention it
不过她曾经说服Gibson先生
but she has managed to persuade Mr. Gibson
资助一项让部族重新定居的慈善计划
to finance a mission of mercy to resettle tribes.
特别是Bororo部族的印第安人
In particular the Bororo Indians
他们已经成为了
who have fallen victim
肆无忌惮的金子和橡胶的勘探者的残害对象
to unscrupulous gold and rubber prospectors.
这种冒险活动现在十分猖獗
The venture is thriving.
我们在学校里见到了你的画像
We saw your pictures in the school.
就像那些英勇的印第安人
Like so many of those warrior Indians
Gibson先生有时候
Mr. Gibson can sometimes give people
会给人一种令人误解的印象
a misleading impression.
Dunbar小姐
Now Miss. Dunbar,
能不能告诉我们那天晚上 到底发生了什么?
will you tell us exactly what happened that evening?
那天早上我收到了Gibson太太的一张便条
I received a note from Mrs. Gibson in the morning.
恳求我在晚饭后 到桥上去见她
It implored me to meet her at the bridge after dinner.
那张便条你有没有留着?
This note, did you keep it?
没有
No.
她要求我把便条毁掉
She asked me to destroy it and to hide my answer
再把我的回复藏在花园的日晷那里
at the sundial in the garden.
我不明白为什么要这么偷偷摸摸
I saw no reason for such secrecy
但她很怕她的丈夫
but she was very much afraid of her husband
他待她十分粗暴
who treated her with a harshness
为此我还经常责备他
by which I frequently reproached him.
我只能想像
I can only imagine that she did not wish him
她不希望他知道我们的会面
to know of our interview.
然而她非常小心地保存着你的答复
Yet she kept your reply very carefully.
是的 听到她死时手里还拿着它
Yes, I was surprised to hear she had it
我感到十分意外
in her hand when she died.
后来又发生了什么?
Well what happened then?
她等着我
She was waiting for me.
你到底是来了
So you have come.
直到那一刻我才意识到
Never did I realize
她有多么恨我
until that moment how much she hated me.
*西班牙语*
(Spanish).
她就像是个疯婆子
She was like a madwoman.
我想她的确是疯了
I think she was mad with a deep power of deception
带着疯子所有的那种自我欺骗
which insane people may have.
你真是残忍 你连心都没有
You're cruel, you have no heart
你不知道如何去爱
You don't know how to love.
你没有激情
You have no passion.
她每天见到我
How else could she have met me
又怎能不忧心忡忡呢
without concern every day.
她就在桥上站着
She was standing there on the bridge
尖叫着诅咒我
shrieking her curses at me.
英国荡妇
English whore.
*西班牙语*
(Spanish)
我诅咒终有一天你会被烧死
I curse the day that you were born.
假设你离开不久她就被杀了
And yet presuming that she met her death
你并没有听到枪声?
shortly after you left, you heard no shot.
没有 我什么也没听到
No, I heard nothing.
她可怕的发作
I was so agitated and horrified
使我又惊又怕
by her terrible outbreak
我冲回房间以寻求安宁
that I rushed to get back to the peace of my own room.
我完全没有注意到所发生的事情
I was incapable of noticing anything that happened.
你自己的房间
Your own room,
第二天早晨之前你离开过吗?
did you leave it again before the next morning?
是的 就在他们把那可怜的女人
Yes, when they brought the poor creature
搬回屋的时候
back to the house.
你觉得Gibson先生是不是看上去十分不安?
Did Mr. Gibson seem to you much perturbed?
他是一个自制力很强的人
He is a very strong self-contained man.
我认为
I do not think
他从来都不会把情绪写在脸上
he would ever show his emotions on the surface.
但是你是如此了解他
But you, who knew him so well.
是的 我可以看出他深深的忧虑
Yes, I could see that he was deeply concerned.
现在我们来谈最重要的一点
Now we come to the all-important point.
那把手枪是在你房间里发现的
This pistol that was found in your room,
你以前从未见过它吗?
you'd never seen it before?
从来没有 我发誓
Never, I swear it.
是什么时候发现的?
When was it found?
第二天早上警察搜查的时候
Next morning when the police made their search.
是的 就在你的衣服中吗?
Yes, among your clothes?
是的 在我衣柜的底部
Yes at the bottom of my wardrobe
其中一个抽屉里
in one of the drawers.
你想不出它在那儿有多久了
And you cannot guess how long it had been there.
事发当天早上之前它不可能在那儿
It could not have been there the morning before
因为我整理过衣柜
because I tidied out the wardrobe.
那么你是说有人进了你的房间
So you're suggesting that someone came into your room
并把它放在那里想嫁祸给你?
and placed it there in order to incriminate you?
应该是这样
It must have been so.
什么时候?
When?
只有可能是吃饭的时候
Well it could only have been at mealtime
要不就是
or else during the hours
在我和孩子们呆在学习室的时候
when I would be in the schoolroom with the children.
也就是你收到便条的时候
As you were when you received the note.
是的 从那时开始
Yes, from that time onward
整个早上
for the whole morning.
谢谢 Dunbar小姐
Thank you Miss. Dunbar.
还有什么线索
Is there any other point
对我的调查有帮助呢?
which could help me in my investigation?
我想不起还有什么
I could think of none.
福尔摩斯 我可以跟你私下谈谈吗?
Holmes, might I have a word with you in private?
请原谅 Dunbar小姐
Forgive me Miss. Dunbar.
福尔摩斯 我愿意把我的案子给你办
Holmes I'd like to put you my case for believing
是因为我相信Gibson先生才是凶手
that Mr. Gibson is the murderer of his wife.
他自己也坦言
We have a man who by his own admission
他习惯了毁掉那些挡他道的人
is used to breaking people who stand in his path,
而他的妻子恰好就是挡了他的道
well his wife stood in his path.
但是Dunbar小姐拒绝了他
But then Miss. Dunbar rejected him.
于是还有什么比杀了一个
Now what better than to kill the one
而嫁祸给另一个更好的法子呢?
and incriminate the other?
真可谓是 一石二鸟之计
To kill the two birds with the one stone so-to-speak.
你不认为
You don't believe that
Gibson的自述是诚恳的?
Gibson's confession was sincere?
Bates不是说了嘛
Wasn't it Bates who said
他是个善于花言巧语又诡计多端的人?
he was plausible and cunning?
他的自述也许是一种聪明的伎俩
His confession was a clever means
想让我们迷失方向
to put us off the scent.
这样想想吧
Think of it like this.
他不知怎么发现了
He somehow discovers
他的妻子安排了一次会面
that his wife has arranged a meeting.
白天的时候他从盒子里拿出了枪
During the day he takes the two pistols from the box.
其中一把打了一发子弹后
One he conceals in the drawer of her wardrobe
被藏入了她的衣柜
after discharging one barrel,
他可以在树林里轻易地开上一枪
which he could easily do in the woods
而不引起别人的注意
without attracting attention.
整个晚上他都是一个人
He is alone all that evening.
他看见Dunbar小姐回来就抓住了机会
He sees Miss. Dunbar return and grasps his opportunity.
他犯下罪行之后
He commits the deed and flings the murder weapon
就把武器远远地丢进了湖里
far into the lake.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
华生 我思维迟钝
Watson, I have been sluggish in mind
缺乏把想象与现实结合的能力
and wanting in that mixture of imagination and reality
这可是我破案的基础啊
which is the basis of my art.
你让我非常羞愧
You have put me entirely to shame.
你会听到我的消息的 Cummings先生
You'll be hearing from me Mr. Cummings
我得到了正义之神
with the help of the god of justice
和我的同事华生医生的帮助
and my colleague Dr. Watson,
我将会给你一个让整个英国轰动的案子
I will give you a case that will make England ring.
Dunbar小姐 我向你保证
Miss. Dunbar you have my assurance
在真相的曙光的照耀下
that the clouds are lifting
疑云正在消散
under the light of truth is breaking through.
来吧 华生 来
Come Watson, come.
我们需要我们的好朋友Coventry警官
We need our good friend Sergeant Coventry
还有一个结实的线团
a ball of stout twine,
和一个抓勾
and a grappling hook.
抓勾?
Grappling hook?
华生 我记得
Watson, I have some recollection that
我们出来办案的时候你多半带着枪
you go armed on these little excursions of ours.
幸好我这样做
Just as well for you that I do.
我的左轮手枪
More than once my revolver has been
可不只一次成了你的好朋友
a good friend to you.
你很少在意自身的安危
You have little care of your own safety.
是的 在这种事情上
Yes, I am inclined to be absent minded
我总是心不在焉
in these matters.
你现在带了左轮手枪吗?
Do you have your revolver on you?
很重 出奇地重
It's heavy, remarkably heavy.
很结实的玩意儿
Solid bit of work.
你知道吧
You know I believe this is going to have
我觉得这把枪和我们正在调查的疑案
a very intimate connection
有着很密切的联系
with the mystery that we're investigating.
你不介意把子弹退出来吧?
Would you mind unloading it?
今天晚上你在家吗 Gibson先生?
Will you be at home this evening Mr. Gibson?
我有消息要带给你
I shall have some news for you.
你可以有半天时间 福尔摩斯先生
You have half a day Mr. Holmes.
以前你看见过我出错 华生
You have seen me miss my mark before Watson.
对这些事情我有一种本能
I have an instinct for such things
但是这种本能有时也会误导我
but it has some times played me false.
我们只能试一试
We can but try.
你们两个可否准确地站在尸体所在的地方?
Will you both stand exactly where the body lay?
你关于这位金矿之王的理论
Your theory about the gold king,
虽然从心理学的角度讲令人钦佩
though admirable in its psychology
却并不接近事实
did not quite adhere to the facts.
把你自己代入这个女人的角色
Visualize yourself in the character of a woman
她冷酷地预谋着
who in a cold premeditated fashion
要除去她的对手
is about to get rid of her rival.
我指的当然是Maria Gibson太太
I mean of course Mrs. Maria Gibson.
因为你把Gibson当作罪犯的
For all your deductions about Gibson
所有理论
being the perpetrator of this crime,
都可以用他太太来替入
substitute his wife.
想像是她
Imagine that it was she
从枪火室里拿走了手枪
who took the pistols from the gunroom,
在树林里开了一枪
who fired the single shot in the woods,
把枪放在Dunbar小姐的衣柜里
who placed the gun in Miss. Dunbar's wardrobe.
冷酷 狡猾
Cold, crafty,
对每一个细节
premeditated,
都预先做出谋划
down to the last detail.
这是否就是事实?
Was it ever an exact demonstration?
我的左轮手枪 福尔摩斯
My revolver Holmes.
一个充满报复心的女人
A vindictive woman
一个热带来的人
a creature of the tropics,
充满激情 情绪不稳定
passionate, ill-balanced.
掩盖了她自己被害的真相
Disguising her own crime and fostering
挑起了对无辜受害者的谋杀指控
a charge of murder upon an innocent victim.
你帮助了一个非凡的女人 福尔摩斯
You have helped a remarkable woman, Holmes
和一个强悍的男人
and a formidable man.
他们在一起
And if it seems
并非是不可能的事
that unlikely they should join forces?
自然我会祝他们一切顺利
Naturally I would wish them well.
你真是心地高尚 华生
Magnanimous of you Watson.
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入
welcome to www.1000fr.com